Guide to the Baugh and Sons Company photographs and advertisements, 1905-1932 RL.00091
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Baugh and Sons Company photographs and advertisements
1905-1932
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Baugh and Sons Company (Philadelphia, Pa.)
RL.00091
0.5 Linear Feet 101 items
Producers and distributors of phosphate fertilizer and agricultural chemicals, based in Philadelphia, and Norfolk, Va. Collection includes photographs and advertisements of the Baugh and Sons Company, a chemical distributor associated with Baugh Chemical Company of Baltimore. Topics include offices, factories, products, personnel, and crops. Farm scenes are from New Jersey, Pennsylvania, and North Carolina.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Baugh and Sons Company photographs and advertisements were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift.
Biographical Note
Producers and distributors of phosphate fertilizer and agricultural chemicals, based in Philadelphia, and Norfolk, Va.
Collection Overview
Photographs and advertisements of the Baugh and Sons Company, a chemical distributor associated with Baugh Chemical Company of Baltimore. Topics include offices, factories, products, personnel, and crops. Farm scenes are from New Jersey, Pennsylvania, and North Carolina.
Collection Arrangement
Photographs are arranged by image number assigned by the company, followed by unnumbered and oversize photographs.
Advertising -- Agriculture; Agriculture -- New Jersey; Agricultural chemicals industry -- United States; Agriculture -- Pennsylvania; Agriculture -- North Carolina; Industries -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia; Agriculture -- United States; Fertilizer industry -- United States; Baugh and Sons Company (Philadelphia, Pa.); Baugh Chemical Company (Baltimore, Md.)
- Photographs and Advertisements, 1905-1932, 1 box, 1 oversize folder
  - Numbered Photographs
    - Asparagus field (Box 1, Print 2A)
    - Benjamin Harris Brewster, 1872-1941, President of Baugh and Sons, 1932 (Includes signature) (Box 1, Print 4)
    - Potato field, 1911 Almanac (Box 1, Print 9A)
    - Ship at dock, 1908 Almanac (Box 1, Print 38-A)
    - Norfolk, Va., Office (Box 1, Print 49-A-1)
    - Machinery (Ovens) (Box 1, Print 54-A)
    - Bag of phosphate (Box 1, Print 108-A)
    - Potato field with men and equipment, 1911 (Box 1, Print 125-A)
    - Shelf display of Baugh products, including view of Delaware River Chemical Works, circa 1905 (Box 1, Print 126-A-2)
    - Bone shed and workers at a Baugh & Sons plant (Box 1, Print 129-A)
    - Cornfield and farm buildings, Hackensack, N.J. (Box 1, Print 155)
    - Farm workers and outbuildings, Hackensack, N.J. (Box 1, Print 157)
    - Cornfield with farmer and equipment (Box 1, Print 164)
    - Cornfield and equipment (Box 1, Print 170)
    - Cornfield on James Wharton Farm, Newtown Square, Pa., 1910 (Box 1, Print 175)
    - Potato field, Garrison Farm, Bridgeton, 1910 (Box 1, Print 176)
    - Potato field, Mich Farm, 1910 (Box 1, Print 180)
    - Potato field, Mich Bros., 1910 (Box 1, Print 186)
    - Mat for 1914 raw bone manures ad (Box 1, Print 207)
    - Mat for Supplemental to Baugh's Booklet (Box 1, Print 218)
    - Potato field, farm buildings in background (Box 1, Print 453-A)
    - Hay field with men (Box 1, Print 456)
    - Hay field with men (Box 1, Print 458-B)
    - Hay field with men (similar to 456) (Box 1, Print 459)
    - Hay field with men and equipment (Box 1, Print 463)
    - Potato field with men, 1911 (Box 1, Print 481)
    - Potato field, 1911 (Box 1, Print 482)
    - Potato field, 1911 (Box 1, Print 484)
    - Potato field (Box 1, Print 485)
    - Office and desk at Baugh & Sons, Jan., 1905 (Box 1, Print 561B)
    - Mr. C. Howard Ward's house (Box 1, Print 612-A)
    - Mr. C. Howard Ward's house (Box 1, Print 612-B)
    - Family on porch of house (Box 1, Print 637)
    - Bag of Baugh's 12 & 5 phosphate and potash (Box 1, Print 698)
    - Office of J. Watson Craft (dealer in lumber, coal, flour, fertilizer, grain and feed), with personnel in front, Amblen Pa., 1913 (Box 1, Print 776)
    - Mat for 1911 raw bone manures ad (Box 1, Print 810)
    - Burton's Point, docks and building (Box 1, Print 838)
    - 3-A Crop field with men and Baugh & Sons sign, 865
      - Empty bags of Baugh & Sons products displayed, 1911 Almanac (Box 1, Print 94)
      - Street scene, town unknown, with store of Charles A. Long, dealer in fertilizer, etc. (Box 1, Print 292-A)
    - Dried cornstalk (Box 1, Print 886)
    - Mat for Baugh's Farmers' 1911 Almanac (Box 1, Print 890)
    - Potato field with farmer and equipment (Box 1, Print 924)
    - Potato field with farmer and horse (Box 1, Print 931)
    - Fire at Union Petroleum Oil Work, 1913 (Box 1, Print 949)
    - Potato field with workers during harvesting, and wagon, 1914 Almanac (Box 1, Print 976)
    - Cornfield with man and boy, 1914 Almanac (Box 1, Print 988)
    - Baugh & Sons display and personnel, probably at a fair (Box 1, Print 996)
    - Baugh & Sons exhibit at New York State Fruit Growers Assoc., Rochester, N.Y., 1914 (Box 1, Print 1023)
    - Bone shed and workers at a Baugh & Sons plant (Box 1, Print 1041)
    - Potato field, Minch Berry Farm, 1913 (Box 1, Print 1071)
    - Tobacco field and farm buildings (Box 1, Print 1107)
    - Tobacco field of Mr. Jacoby (Box 1, Print 1108)
    - Family on porch of house (Box 1, Print 1126)
    - Cornfield with men, 1914 (Box 1, Print 1135)
    - Man and woman in field (Box 1, Print 1161)
    - Tobacco field of C. E. Hart, Ayden, N.C., 1914 (Box 1, Print 1167)
    - Wm. Wright on farm of Alex C. Ferguson, Burlington, N.J., 1922 (Box 1, Print 1600)
    - Field of ensilage corn, Ephraim T. Gill farm, Haddonfield, N.J., 1922 (Box 1, Print 1638)
    - A portion of a herd of 175 Ayrshire cattle, Mrs. John R. Valentine's Highland Farm, Bryn Mawr, Pa., 1922 (Box 1, Print 1659)
    - A scene around the stables, Highland Farm, 1922 (Box 1, Print 1661)
    - Avenue of French poplar trees, Highland Farm, 1922 (Box 1, Print 1663)
    - A famous hunter (horse) and his keeper, Highland Farm, 1922 (Box 1, Print 1665)
    - Potato field and men, Joseph M. Garrison's farm, Elmer, N.J., 1922 (Box 1, Print 1685)
    - Cotton plant, 1922 (Box 1, Print 1691)
    - Alvarez y Rodriguez display (Box 1, Print 1823)
    - North Carolina cotton crop of W.E. Askew, 1914 and 1923 Almanacs (Box 1, Print 1826)
    - Cornfield and man, U.H. McCarter's Tower Hill Farm, Red Bank, N.J., 1923 (Box 1, Print 1885)
    - Harvesting in Potato field of Minch Bros., 1911 (Box 1, Print 1896)
    - Farm produce stand of Fra. Carhart, Hazlet, Keyport, N.J., 1923. Dealer and farmer. (Box 1, Print 1908)
    - Cornfield and people, 1924 (Box 1, Print 1943)
    - Cornfield of George Stillwell, Hopewell, N.J., 1925 (Box 1, Print 2016)
    - Cornfield of George Stillwell with man in scene, 1925, Hopewell, N.J. (Box 1, Print 2017)
  - Unnumbered Photographs
    - Baugh & Sons Co. and Baugh Chemical Co. offices in Seaboard Bank Bldg., Norfolk, Va. (Box 1)
    - Baugh & Sons Co. and Baugh Chemical Co. offices in building (Box 1)
    - E.T. Short, English Tailor & Importer, New York, store and personnel (Box 1)
    - Plant machinery (Box 1)
    - Bone shed (2) (Box 1)
    - Fertilizer bags (2) (Box 1)
    - Baugh & Sons plant, hay wagon, and trade mark, 1913 Almanac (Box 1)
    - Mat for bone meal bag ad (Box 1)
    - Mat for four fertilizer bags for ad (Box 1)
    - George S. Snyder residence (Box 1)
    - Ship at dock unloading bones (2) (Box 1)
    - Plant scene - bone processing (Box 1)
- Oversize Photographs, 1912-1923 and undated, 2 folders
  - Potato field including buildings, men, and equipment (Box Sec. A OV5, Print 871)
  - Four pictures at least one of which was in 1912 Almanac (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - E. H. Keen & Co., flour, feed, and grain dealer (Box Sec. A OV5, Print 876)
  - Town scene with flags and bunting on buildings (Box Sec. A OV5, Print 386)
  - C. Frank Williamson business (Box Sec. A OV5, Print 390)
  - Philips-Thompson Co.'s Christina Mills and Grain Elevator. Old streetcar also in scene. 1912 Almanac. (Box Sec. A OV5, Print 393)
  - Ship Erhard at dock, 1913 (Box Sec. A OV5, Print 1015)
  - Baugh's plant at dockside, Baltimore. 1922 Almanac. (Box Sec. A OV5, Print 1575)
  - Mat for picture of fertilizer bag. 1923 Almanac. (Box Sec. A OV5, Print 1833-A)
  - Three plant and dockside scenes Nos. 101-A (1912) Almanac), 91-A, 330-A (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - Man with bags of various Baugh fertilizer products (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - George S. Snyder residence and warehouse, Nos. 344-A, 346-A (1912 Almanac). Includes 389-A, unidentified dealer's establishment, and inset of Delaware River Chemical Works (Box Sec. A OV5)